《女子监狱》
第二季第二集
黑人儿童收养节
想听我唱歌吗
Wanna hear my song?
无论从哪个方面来说我都无懈可击
I am beautiful in every single way.
是的  流言蜚语不会击垮我
Yes, words can't bring me down.
哦  不
Oh, no.
你们好  我叫布蕾歇尔
Hi, I'm Brichelle.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - How are you?
布蕾歇尔  你最好给我滚远点儿
Brichelle! You better to fuck off!
这姑娘太冲动
She got impulse-control issues, you know?
我很聪明  我能记住整个元素周期表
I'm real smart. I know the whole periodic chart.
我喜欢科学
I love science!
够了塔莎  去喝点冰沙
Okay, Tasha, how about we get you a shaved ice, yes?
要什么口味儿
What flavor would you like?
-可是我...  -塔莎
- But I was... - Tasha.
蓝色的
Blue.
那东西看着真邪恶
That looks vile.
看着是蓝的  但喝起来跟红的一样
It look blue, but it tastes like red.
红和蓝是颜色  不是口味
Blue and red are colors, darlin'. They're not flavors.
好喝就行  我想喝点好喝的
Well, it's tasty. I like me somethin' tasty.
尤其是今天
Especially on days like now.
大家都喜欢乖孩子
People only want the babies.
人家当然喜欢乖孩子  多可爱呀
Of course they want the babies. Babies are cute.
我也可爱
I'm cute.
不  你块头太大  头发太爆炸
No, you're big, and your hair's ratsy.
太心急  肤色太黑
And you're too eager and too dark.
现在嘴还是蓝的了  估计味道是红的吧
And now your mouth is blue, but I suppose it tastes like red.
你嘴真毒
You nasty.
我只是实话实说
I just call 'em like I see 'em, darlin'.
你的教养院在附近吗
Your group home in this neighborhood?
你怎么知道我在教养院
How you know I live in a group home?
孩子  这个手感有点轻呢
My dear boy, this feels light to me.
轻了就不对  除非你想睡大街
Light ain't right unless you like sleeping on the street.
不是轻  都是大票
Nah, it ain't light. It's just big bills.
那就晚上吃饭见
Well, then, I'll see you at home for dinner, baby.
我去  原来你是毒贩子
Aw, shit, you a connect.
我是女商人
I'm a businesswoman.
我刚才听到你在那边秀科学
I couldn't help hear you braggin' on your science back there.
有两下子
I'm impressed.
我还知道π
I also know pi.
从你屁股就看得出你知道派
Your ass tells me you know pie.
派和π同音
π  不是派
Pi. Not "pie".
我能背小数点后56位
Up to 56 digits.
你想学做买卖吗
You care to learn the trade?
才不呢  才不跟毒贩子学
Hell, no, not with no connect.
要是出了事  就没哪一家会收养我了
I get in trouble, I never find a forever family.
你该考虑
You might wanna start thinkin' about
自成一家了  美味
making your own forever family, Taystee.
老是等别人救  会等到死
You wait around for one to come along, you might die waitin'.
我叫塔莎
My name is Tasha.
但美味跟你很搭
Yeah, but Taystee suits you somehow.
我刚说了  谁都喜欢"美味"的东西
Like you said, everybody like a little somethin' tasty.
我会盯住你的  美味
I'll be keepin' my eye on you, Taystee Girl.
回见
See you around the way.
太美了
This is sweet!
要不是扮职业装  老娘一定要火一把
Yo, I'd rock this if I wasn't being all professional.
管那么多干嘛  反正都是搞着玩
Why you care? You know it's all bullshit.
管他是不是搞着玩  我就想赢
Bullshit or no, I wanna win!
好好打扮是为了留下良好的第一印象
Ladies, it's about making a good first impression.
有白色的吗  我妈妈说白色最衬我
You got anything in white? My mother always said that was my color.
这衣服以前都谁穿过  各种味儿都有
Ugh! I mean, you could smell every inmate that's ever worn this.
这破烂你都洗过吗
You ever wash this shit?
有给大号美女穿的吗
You got something for the larger woman? Big and beautiful?
那边有加大码
We have plus size on the end there.
靠  人家才不要穿麻袋呢
Aw, shit. Man, I don't wanna wear no sack.
人家有线条  前凸后翘
I got curves. I'm a plushious woman.
既然是职业装
If this is really about career dressing for us,
为什么不干脆穿麦当劳服务员制服
shouldn't this be all, like, McDonald's and maids' uniforms?
不对  不要目光短浅
No! Do not think small.
要为自己向往的工作打扮
We are dressing ourselves for the career that we want.
要往大了想  为成功打扮
You have to put it into the universe, dress for success.
你穿豹纹
Take the leopard.
我都没看见豹纹  美死了
Oh, I didn't see the leopard! Ooh, that's cute.
我想当海洋生物学家怎么办
What if I wanna be, like, a marine biologist?
有潜水服吗
You got a wet suit?
你要想在那一行找工作
If you want to apply for a job in marine biology,
要先去人家办公室面试
you might have to go to an office for an interview.
这件怎么样
What about this?
粉色和你的肤色很搭
The peach tones would look so good with your skin.
谁来帮我拉一下
Could somebody help zip me, please?
肯定穿不上
I don't think that's gonna work.
你是说我胖吗
You callin' me fat?
没  就说你…有点壮啦
No. I'm just saying that you're... Yeah, you're broad.
是很壮很壮的那种
You're like a broad broad.
你个壮娘们儿
She a broad somethin.'
你个贱娘们儿
And you a bitch somethin.'
我来拉这边
I'm gonna pull in this side here.
-小心小心  -你拉那边
- Careful. Careful. - And you pull in that side.
再来个人拉拉链
And someone's gotta get the zipper.
-肯定能拉上  -好
- Okay, we can do this. - Okay.
我拉拉链  走起  吸气
I'll do the zipper. Let's go. Suck it in, girl.
在吸呢
I am sucking.
靠
Fuck.
天啊
Oh, God.
怎么样
How's it look?
我可不敢离你太近
Like I don't wanna be anywhere near you
免得那些珠子崩掉了  砸到我脸
when those beads pop off and shoot people in the face.
我好奇的是
Out of curiosity,
你穿这身是要想找什么工作
what kind of job were you thinking of gettin' in that?
人家就是想美美地打扮一次
I'm just here playin' dress-up.
姑娘们  快点
Ladies, you better get movin.'
咱们10分钟后去教堂
We're walkin' over to that chapel in 10 minutes.
我还没穿呢
I don't have anything.
麻烦问一下
Hey, can I ask you something?
要是去面试一家尤蒂卡的药品公司
What would you wear if you were going to a job interview
该穿什么呢
at a medical supply company in Utica?
我就假设一下
Just hypothetically speaking.
为什么弗娜卡去招聘会我们却要待在这里
How come Flaca gets to do job fair and we're stuck here?
因为弗娜卡先申请
'Cause Flaca asked first,
我要是让你们都去  就没人干活了
and if I let everybody go, nobody would be here.
下次早申请
Next time, ask first.
她根本不需要招聘会
She don't even need job fair.
她男朋友是莫利大王
Her boyfriend's like the king of molly.
给纽约所有夜店供货
He be selling to every club kid in New York.
那玩意儿爽嗨了
That shit is blowing up.
莫利是什么
What's molly?
纯摇头丸粉
The pure powder form of MDMA.
应该是纯净的摇头丸  但我吸老是磨牙
Supposed to be like a clean ecstasy, but it made me grind my teeth.
老天不开眼  你怎么没进监狱
How come you ain't in jail, Luschek?
我不是已经进来了嘛  天天都在
I am in jail, every fuckin' day.
你想把暖气片关掉还是打开
You want the radiator on or off?
关掉  这里面已经够热了
Off. It's hot enough in here.
其他地方都冻得要死
And freezing everywhere else.
我们厕所的管道又冻住了  怎么办
The pipes in our bathroom froze again, how about deal with that?
我又不是管道工
I'm not a plumber.
不好意思  因为你露着春光呢  我以为...
Oh, our mistake, you got that whole ass-crack thing going, so...
你想吃点苦头吗
Inmate, you want me to give you a shot?
来块招聘会布朗尼蛋糕吧
Hey, have a job fair brownie.
玛丽亚  别在这贫嘴  洗碗去
Maria, stop running your mouth and run the dishwasher.
达娅  看我有东西给你
Daya? Ven, I've got something for you.
天啊  我快死了
Thank God. I'm dying.
这有用吗
Is this gonna work?
应该有用  一口气喝完
It should. Drink up, mami.
你给她喝什么
What are you giving her over there?
没什么
It's nothing.
帮她拉大便  她便秘
It's to help her poop. She's backed up.
为什么不跟我说呢
Why didn't you tell me?
-厕所里的事你想听吗  -当然
- You don't wanna hear about my bathroom. - Of course I do.
好吧  阿蕾达
Okay, Aleida.
我五天没大便了  这下开心了吗
I haven't shit for five days, you happy?
真够意思  歌洛丽娅
Thank you, Gloria.
你做什么了
What do you think you're doing?
放宽心
Oh, man, relax.
就是点李子汁加橄榄油
It's prune juice, olive oil, a little magic.
不会伤到宝宝
It's not gonna hurt the baby.
你不是她妈  我才是
You're not her mother, I'm her mother.
你现在倒像是她阿姨
I think right now you're more like her aunt.
不
Uh-uh, no.
我要是她阿姨  那我这一肚子妊娠纹哪来的
I didn't get me a belly full of stretch marks to be no fucking tía.
别激动  她找我帮忙我就帮了她
Look, relax, she came to me, I helped her out.
她跟我在一起自在
She's comfortable with me.
是  自在过头了
Yeah, too comfortable.
如大家所知
So, as you can see,
我们在未来几天里为大家安排了精彩的项目
we have a very exciting few days planned for all of you.
现在闪亮登场的是我们的"为成功打扮"
And now to start things off, here from Dress for Success,
大家将会从中学到
to give you some dos and don'ts
面试着装的注意事项  赛金夫人
of interview dressing, Mrs. Sackin.
谢谢
Thank you.
为成功打扮是帮助
Dress for Success is the premier support network
失业妇女就业的重要一步
for today's unemployed woman.
咱们开始吧  女士们
Let us begin our journey. Ladies?
好了  大家看到的有什么
Okay, right away, what do we see?
酒会礼服显然不是面试着装
That a cocktail dress is not proper interview attire.
这件不够职业 连日间着装都不算
This is not corporate or even daytime wear.
-不算  -太不职业
- Nope. - Wholly unprofessional.
老娘就是来秀身材的
I'm just showing off my assets.
接下来豹纹装  水手服
Next, I'm going to say leopard, little sailor girl,
还有粉色套装  都不是面试着装
and our friend in peach here are also not properly attired for an interview.
动物图案太狂野  说明本人品味不佳
The animal print is too racy and implies poor judgment,
水手服太幼稚
and the sailor outfit is childish.
-公司都想招成年人  -成年人
- Companies are looking to hire adults. - Adults.
最后粉色不合身
And finally, the peach is simply ill-fitting,
显陈旧  而且和肤色不衬
dated, and not flattering.
-但你让我穿的  -没错  你让她穿的
- But you told me to wear it. - Yeah, you did.
我只想和海豚游泳
I just wanna swim with dolphins.
谢谢  各位可以下去了
Thank you, you can leave the stage now.
现在来看看这边几位
Okay, let's look at what's going right up here.
这一身是合适的面试着装
This is a good interview outfit.
很合身
It fits her well.
黑色长筒袜营造保守感  是点睛之笔
The dark stockings give it a conservative, polished finish.
妆容稍显阴暗狠厉
I believe the makeup is a bit gothic and heavy-handed,
但总体来说这身打扮无可挑剔
but overall the look is solid.
无可挑剔  听见没
That's right, solid.
还有一套比较合体的就是衬衣西裤
Another strong ensemble we have is the pantsuit and blouse.
经典打扮
It's classic.
但个人妆容方面
However, we do run into some serious problems
还存在严重问题
with personal grooming here.
什么
Huh?
头发凌乱  没有细心打理
The hair, it's messy, unpolished, unkempt.
-人家头发是干净的  -显得野蛮又懒散
- My hair is clean. - It's wild and slovenly.
我只是不想那么死板
I'm sorry it's not uptight and boring!
但这一位发型整齐
But here, the hair is nicely coiffed,
妆容精致低调
the makeup is subtle and understated.
但衬衣太透  裙子太紧
However, the shirt is too sheer, and the skirt is too tight.
等会儿  打住
Uh-uh, hold up. Pause.
这一身是去年招聘会的赢家  我有看过
At job fair last year, this was the winnin' outfit. I seen it myself.
所以人家才选这身
That's why I picked it instead of
没选那件诱人的蓝色裙子
the blue dress I know I'd look bangin' in.
现在咱们再来聊如何根据身材和肤色搭配
Let's talk a moment about dressing for your body type and your skin tone.
稍微丰满的女士最好选择宽松的外套
A fuller-figured woman might wanna choose a looser-fitting garment,
裙装比衬衣西裤更佳
perhaps a dress as opposed to a shirt and a skirt.
但不能像这位这样宽松  像个麻布袋子
Not as loose as this, which resembles a large burlap muumuu.
可不是
No shit.
要穿宝石颜色裙装  搭撞色围巾
But something in a jewel tone with a contrasting scarf.
-我知道我好看   -我这身还是很职业的
- I know I look good. - Man, I still look hella office.
我一走进办公室  人家肯定想
I walk in, they be like,
"这姑娘有两下子"
"Yeah, she know her business".
没错
Yeah!
那现在谁赢
So, who wins?
总的来说  除去过于浓重的眼妆
Overall, despite the excessive eye makeup,
我认为这位年轻女士获胜
I would have to give it to this young lady right here.
这就对了  拉丁裔获胜
That's right, Latina, we the winna.
你居然让那恰恰怪咖赢了
Man, you gave it to Franken-cha-cha?
简直瞎扯淡
This is some bullshit, shit to the bull.
那毒女请你出去吃饭了吗
Damn, that Kool take you out to dinner first?
你怎么跟玛莎一个口气
Man, you sound just like Marsha.
你知道她就在厨房里吗
You know she right there in that kitchen.
管他呢  这烂地方也就两周好待了
Like I care. Only got two weeks left in this shit hole.
小姑娘  吞云吐雾的样子
Little girl, you look like a dragon with all that
很像龙呢
smoke coming out of your nose.
您老人家抽烟像是路上
Please, you smoke like a hooptie's tailpipe,
老爷车排气管冒烟呢
puffin' up and down the street.
我是成年人  有权选择做坏事
I'm an adult, it gives me the right to make bad choices.
我们要去瑞林饭馆吃好吃的  一起来吗
We heading over to Rayleen's for something delicious. Care to join us?
我要去上班
I gotta work.
我们也上班
Well, we working, too,
但我们上班不会满身酸臭味儿
except our work doesn't leave us smelling like rancid oil.
是  您干净得就像毒贩子
Yeah, you clean as a drug-dealin' whistle.
拒绝别人的邀请只说"不了  谢谢"就行了
You should decline an offer by simply saying, "No, thank you."
不然以后谁还会邀请你
Otherwise, people will stop inviting you to things.
我想去吃
I could eat.
走吧  咱们好好吃一顿去
Well, come on, then, let's nourish that body.
再见  美味
Bye-bye, Taystee Girl.
真不想来一起吃吗
Sure you not tryin' to come out and eat, though?
不了RJ  我要去上班
No, RJ, I gotta get to work.
好吧  注意安全
All right, be safe, though.
后面有鸡肉味杯面吗
Is the chicken flavor Cup of Noodles back in stock,
还是只有虾味
or have you only got the shrimp?
有奶油鸡肉味
We got cream of chicken.
不行  我不喜欢那个
No, I don't like that one.
那你要虾味
You want shrimpy?
好吧  给我来五个
Sure, I'll take five of those,
还有我不要金枪鱼配辣酱  金枪鱼就好
and I don't want the tuna with the spicy sauce, just plain tuna.
咖啡要焦炒的
Oh, and for the coffee, the dark roast, please.
奥尼尔  健身还顺利吧
How's the fitness going, O'Neill?
才到4500步  一天要10000步
I'm in the forty-seven hundreds. Over 10,000 steps a day.
肯定没问题
You'll make it easy,
时间还早呢  你做得不错
it's still early, and good for you.
慢慢来
One step at a time.
-不对  -怎么不对
- Uh-oh, problem. - What kind of problem?
账户里没钱
No-money-in-account problem.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
给家里打电话  没钱卖不了
Call your family. I can't sell you shit.
不好意思  下一位
Sorry, next!
你知道这对我的植物影响多大吗
Do you understand what this is doing to my plants?
我的多肉植物上都结霜了
There was frost on my succulent.
这可是沙漠植物  不能结冻
This is a desert plant, it should not be freezing.
火炉得换新的了
Look, the furnace needs to be replaced.
我就是整天修  它也热不起来
I could dickpaw it all day. It's never getting hot again.
是嘛  就跟你老妈一样
Mmm, like your mother.
又拿人家老娘开玩笑  你真行
Ah, delightful, a "your mama" joke? That's priceless.
菲格怎么说的
What did Fig say?
你说呢  她撩起裙子
What do you think? She hiked up her skirt...
然后呢
Yeah.
让我修补一下
Told me to Band-Aid the old heap
然后给我50块钱
and gave me 50 bucks
让我给她办公室买个取暖器
to buy a space heater for her office.
你就跟的了便宜的小狗一样
And you ran off like a good little puppy
然后给她办了事
and you did it for her.
是她傻
Joke's on her.
取暖器只要27块  我净赚23
Space heater cost 27 bucks, that's 23 bucks profit, man.
够在时时乐[快餐连锁]吃个双人餐了
That's dinner for two at Sizzler.
这是4块钱
Here's $4.
加上之前的23
Add it to the 23.
给我整个取暖器  不然我就去告你
Buy me one of those space heaters, or I'm gonna rat you out.
时时乐吃不了咯
No Sizzler for you.
妈的
Shit.
各位注意  每餐只能含有1500卡路里
Don't forget, ladies, your usual meal is 1,500 calories.
小心长胖
Beware of overeating.
你的狗狗呢
Hey, where's your doggy?
看我给你带了什么  乖  乖
Look what I got, look what I got. That's right, that's right.
爱吃吧  这就对了
Oh! You love that, don't you? Yeah, yeah.
舔吧舔吧  爱吃黄油花生对吧
You just lick, lick, lick. You like peanut butter, don't you?
爱舔就好好舔
You like to lick that, don't you? Oh, just lick, lick, lick.
舔
Lick.
还是不说的好
It got weird.
那好吧
Oh, okay.
看谁来了
Look who's here.
要跟歌洛丽娅说吗
Should I tell Gloria?
几周前歌洛丽娅说红妈可以吃了
Nah, a few weeks ago, Gloria said the roja could eat,
但直到今天才来
but she just never came in till now.
干嘛要放她一马
Why'd she let her off the hook?
你想啊  她丢了厨房
Well, you got to figure, she lost her kitchen,
没了小妹  头发还搞成那烂样
she lost her girls, and her hair is all fucked up.
赐她点剩饭  让她苟延残喘吧
Let her have some shitty food and get on with her life.
要我说
If it was up to me,
就不应该再让她进来
I'd never let her back in here.
她可是只熊
That's a bear.
俄罗斯大熊
A big Russian bear.
现在
And right now
她只是在蛰伏期等着东山再起
she's hibernating until she gets strong again
到时候那熊会后脚站立
and she's gonna stand up on her back legs
用熊爪和熊牙
and she's gonna shred up
把大家都撕了
everybody with her bear claws and her bear teeth.
你他妈好像很懂熊
What the fuck do you know about bears?
你住在布朗克斯动物园旁边吗
What, you live by the Bronx Zoo or somethin'?
布朗克斯动物园  位于纽约最北部
世界十大动物园之一
红熊
Red bear.
你看她眼睛就知道
You can see it in her eyes.
你就满嘴放屁
You're full of shit.
达娅才是满肚子屁
No, Daya's the one who's full of shit.
还真是
It's true.
现在说这个好笑吗  我心情不好
It's not funny right now, I'm not in a good way.
是  我们的"屎命"就是不拿她开玩笑
She's right, it's our "doodie" not to make fun of her.
因为那玩笑太"屎"了
Yeah, 'cause that would be crappy.
你俩就是大烂货
You guys are such assholes.
asshole双关骂人和屁眼儿
但烂货的屁眼儿还挺管用
At least these assholes are working. Oh, snap!
囚犯马丁内兹  请到洗衣房报到
Inmate Martinez, report for an assignment at the laundry detail.
看谁来了
Ook-lay oo's-hay ere-hay.
够谨慎  莫里洛
Subtle, Morello.
我还是觉得不适应
It's just still throwing me, you know?
看她没穿主厨的马甲
Not seeing her in her chef's jacket, you know?
就像看见昨晚跟你姐姐上床的条子
It's like when you see a cop in sweat pants in your kitchen
今天穿着运动裤在你家厨房溜达
after he's spent the night with your sister.
裤子上还有精液痕迹  感觉好诡异
Little splooge on the sweat pants, and you feel weird about it.
她说她能看到幻象
She said she's seeing some shit.
她吃精神病药吃嗨了
She's high as a kite on psych meds.
真可怜
That's too bad.
一起吃吧
Care to join us?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
这里不错  又安静  不过谢谢
Happy here, nice and quiet, but thank you.
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
她来了
There she is.
佩
Penn.
嗨
Hi.
没想到还能见到你  还好吗
We didn't think we were ever gonna see you again, what happened?
我只记得我是一个天使
Last thing I remember is I was an angel.
听说你俩打得很凶
Well, I heard y'all beat the holy mess out of each other.
我估计她被揍得够呛
Yeah, I mean, I suppose she got a few licks in.
那回头见吧
Well, talk to you later.
我明白
I understand.
你想跳舞吗
Would you like to dance?
费歇尔  你好吗
Hey, Fischer, how you doing?
很好长官  多谢关心  一切已经恢复正常
Fine, sir, thanks for asking, back in the swing of things.
很好  德盖特  坐
Good to hear. Doggett, take a seat.
麻烦关上门
Would you close the door, please?
出禁赛区了是吗
So, out of the penalty box, huh?
什么
I'm sorry, what?
没什么  禁赛区  曲棍球术语
Nothing. Penalty box. Hockey?
没有  不是曲棍球  海利长官
No, no, no. No hockey, Mr. Healy.
我进了禁闭室
I've been in SHU.
我被关了一个月吧  是一个月吗
It's been like a month, I think, right? A month? Yeah.
然后人家把我拉出来  说我可以回来了
So they just pulled me out, said I was back.
那我回来了吗
Am I back?
暂时
For now.
你肯定想知道为什么我把你叫来这里
I suppose you're wondering why I called you down here.
心理辅导  怕我再发疯
Uh, counseling? Make sure I don't go cuckoo again?
我不会的  我脑子清醒着呢
I won't. I got all my marbles back.
我觉得咱们应该好好谈谈
I thought we should talk.
把事情谈明白
Get things straight.
好吧
All right.
我敢保证我现在
I mean, I can promise you that
神智特清醒
I've never felt more saner than I do now.
一个人关禁闭关那么久
You know, when you spend that much time down there in solitude,
就像是心灵净化  我心灵现在很平静
it's like real purification. You know, my heart feels right.
你应该有很多时间可以反省那晚的事吧
I suppose you had time to reflect on that evening, then?
没有  因为我头很晕
Nope, because my head is so fuzzy.
是吗
Oh? Is that so?
我身上那么多青肿
I mean, I suffered multiple contusions and...
和撕裂伤  疼痛都够我受了
lacerations, and it's just freakin' painful,
现在我恢复了
and now that I got through it,
渐渐开始回想起
I started to remember,
当时的好多事
and then lots of stuff came back to me.
是的
Yep.
她惹毛你  你就去找她对峙然后打了起来
She angered you, you confronted her, and you fought.
没错
Yes.
对吗  就这样
That's it, end of story.
不是  还有
No, there's more.
还有什么
What more?
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
看我站谁这边儿
There's, like, angles, and there's, like,
或者酌情减刑什么的
extenuations and then there's...
我不知道我看到了什么  德盖特
I didn't know what I was seeing, Doggett.
你听明白了吗
Do you hear what I'm saying?
我不知道你俩要...
I had no idea that you two were gonna...
你们俩可能是在说话呢
You could have been having a talk,
比如情人拌嘴
a lovers' quarrel, even, I don't know,
我没看见武器
and I certainly didn't see a weapon.
一放假  气氛就开始紧张
Holiday times, tensions get high.
谁知道卡佳怎么那么暴躁
I mean, God knows Katya was testier than ever then,
但你别以为
but don't think for a second
有人会相信你个吸冰毒的瘾君子而不是我
that anyone is gonna believe a meth-addled hillbilly over me.
这你要清楚
Be 100% fucking clear about that.
那他们万一...
Well, they might just...
偏偏相信我这个生存权运动的代表人物呢
believe the poster girl for the right-to-life movement.
我可上过格雷塔・范・苏思腾的采访
You know, I was on Greta Van Susteren,
格雷塔・范・苏思腾  评论家兼电视名人
你说他们要是知道你想害死我  会怎样
and what if they knew you were about to let me get killed?
我就应该关你禁闭  让你自生自灭
I ought to throw you back in seg and let you rot.
怎么才能让你忘了你看到的东西
What would help you forget what you think you saw?
我还是不明白这跟预算的问题有什么关系
Uh, I'm still not sure how that answers the questions I have regarding the budget.
所以我今天才邀请你过来
That's why I invited you today.
我们的"为成功打扮"项目  还有招聘会
Programs like Dress for Success, our job fair,
圣诞聚会  读书会
our Christmas pageant, Readers to Readers,
这些虽然不是惩教署的要务
are not a top priority for the DOC,
但对争取犯人人心
but they are so important for morale,
对教育和劳改大有好处
for education, for rehabilitation.
在我们争取到政府的支持  推行改革前
Until we can get the government on board for some serious reform,
资金用途进行微调非常有必要
a little shifting of funds is a necessity,
但我向你保证  所有款项
but I assure you all of the money is being used
全都被用来改善监狱环境和狱友生活上
for the good of the prison and its residents.
好吧
Okay.
我还注意到  你丈夫在竞选州参议员
And I noticed that your husband is running for state senate.
他也支持你的教育主张吗
Is your passion for education a value he shares?
当然
Absolutely.
你如果对杰森有任何问题
Uh, but any questions you have for Jason,
可直接联系他办公室
you can direct towards his office.
希望我的解释能够让你
I hope I've shed some light on how the money
对利奇菲尔德的资金使用情况有些了解
is being used to benefit the inmates here at Litchfield.
其实我还有些问题...
Uh, well, actually, I've got a few more questions...
不好意思  我还有工作要忙
Because I'm afraid, sadly, I have to get back to work.
监狱也需要人管理
Prison doesn't run itself.
那身衣服是她给我的  明明就是设计我
I mean, she gave me the freakin' outfit. It was one big setup.
结果那俩黑姑娘  一个同性恋瘾君子
So now the two black girls, the lesbo junkie girl,
一个墨西哥女的进入面试环节
and some Mexican get to go on and do the interview part,
我却被淘汰了
and I'm back here.
但你化的妆很好看呀
Well, your makeup looks real pretty.
我直到那天才知道你有睫毛膏
Like, I didn't even know you had eyelashes till today.
你很漂亮
You look really nice.
谢谢你小安  就你会宽我心
Thanks, Ange. That's nice of you to say.
知道吗  佩从你禁闭出来了
Hey, did you know that Penn's out of seg?
-什么  -没错
- What? - Mmm-hmm.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
因为午餐后我看到她去海利的办公室
'Cause I seen her, after lunch, walking to Healy's office.
她怎么样
How'd she look?
样子很惨
She looked pretty rough.
本来她牙就不好  现在更没几个剩
I mean, if her teeth was bad before? Woof, ain't much left in there.
汤普森警卫请到塔上来
Guard Thompson to the tower.
别误解我意思  但自从她走后
Don't get me wrong or nothin, ' but since she's been away,
这里一下子好过了些
hasn't it been, like, kind of nice in here?
-怎么讲  -我也说不好
- What do you mean? - I don't know, like...
就是很平静  很舒服
like, peaceful, easy.
没有大吼大叫  没有到处叫人去死
No yelling, no telling everyone they're going to hell, just...
就是很安静
Just quiet, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
你不会告诉她吧
But you won't tell her I said nothing, right?
当然不会啦
'Course not.
女士们  请去任务板领取任务
Ladies, check the board for work assignments.
帕波现在在哪里
So, where's Piper now?
还在芝加哥吧我估计
Still in Chicago, I imagine it.
莱瑞  我想说的是你  不是她
Larry, I wanted to talk about you, not her.
她还在芝加哥
She staying there? In Chicago?
她不喜欢深盘披萨
She hates deep-dish.
芝加哥以特色深盘披萨而出名
不知道她会不会留在芝加哥
Don't know if she's staying.
也不知道她吃不吃披萨
Don't think she's eating a whole lot of pizza.
-莱瑞  -她看起来如何
- Larry... - How'd she seem to you?
就是一傻瓜  我给她建议她不听
Seemed like an idiot to me. I gave her advice, and she didn't take it.
你爱她她却背叛你
You gave her love, and she cheated on you.
我不喜欢她  不聊她了
I'm not a fan, and end of topic.
-我想她  -那就找点其他消遣吧
- I miss her. - Well, then, find a distraction, son,
不要像现在这样行尸走肉  食不知味
something that doesn't involve moping around, eating crap
-还整天打"魔术世界"  -"魔兽世界"
- and playing that World of Warlock. - Warcraft.
魔兽  好吧
Warcraft, perfect.
还能去参加坦克部队  又是浪费时间
You can join the tank corps, another waste of time.
魔兽世界字面意思为"战舰世界"
去找姑娘吧
Go get laid.
-我还没准备好  -准备什么
- I'm not ready. - For what?
没准备好把自己老二放在新山洞里快活吗
For sticking your dick in something new and cute and moving it around?
哪个男的都说上就能上
All guys are ready for that.
我这俩兄弟时刻都准备着
These two over here are ready for it any moment now.
你的生活还要继续
Get on with your life.
没错  你说的没错
You're right. No, you're right.
是她先背叛我的
She cheated, right? I mean...
她骗我  我为什么还放不下
She lied, why am I holding on?
监狱改变了她  改变了人心
Prison changed her. It changes people.
-可不是   -她本来已经不是蕾丝了
- I heard that. - I mean, she was not a lesbian anymore,
跟我一起时就不是
not with me.
然后进监狱几周  又成蕾丝了
You know? Then she's in prison, what, a few weeks? Bam! A lesbian again.
或者说男女通吃  我不知道
Or bi? I don't even know.
我俩爱爱很激情  我很清楚
It was good with us, I know it was.
妈的  如果那也是骗我的呢
I think, shit, I mean, what if that was a lie, too?
但我觉得又不像  我觉得不像
But I don't think it was, I don't think it was, I mean,
我还是有两下子的  给力又到位
you know, I know I have some talent, I'm very attentive and thorough,
功夫不是盖的  我又不小
you know, I do good work, I'm not small.
-莱瑞  -没错  我该去另寻佳人
- Larry. - You're right, I should get out there.
我得忘记她  我会这么做的
I need to get out there. I'm gonna get out there.
我能让她达到阴道高潮
I made her come vaginally,
你知道做起来多难吗
do you know how hard that is to do?
-拜托莱瑞   -我想说的是...
- Please, Larry. - My point is...
我也不知道我想说什么来着
I don't even know what my point is anymore.
-爸  -什么
- Dad? - Yeah?
你干嘛带我来基佬浴室
Why did you bring us to a gay bathhouse?
好地方  干净  蒸浴就是蒸浴
It's a nice place, clean. A shvitz is a shvitz.
-我有团购票  -明白了
- I had a Groupon. - Ah, gotcha.
那这个可以写在简历上吗
Wait, so, I could put that on my resume thing?
-为我堂兄工作  -当然
- Workin' for my cousin? - Sure.
但你不要说你看场子
But instead of saying that you helped make sure
防止人偷东西
that no one stole shit,
可以说你负责
you could say that you monitored inventory
监控库存和保安工作
and provided security.
好的  明白了  这个我看行
Ah, okay, okay, I see that, I could do that.
我想要一种淡定的工作
I want the kind of job where I could just chill, you know?
淡定  然后能拿钱
Chill out, collect a check.
根据能力测试  我应该成为专业运动员
According to this aptitude test, I should be a professional athlete,
公园管理员  还有教改官
a park ranger, or a correctional officer.
在斯塔奇店做过
Working at Storky's
说明我有食品行业工作经验
means I have experience in the food service industry.
没错
That's it.
然后我记性好  算加法快
And because I can remember shit and add real fast,
说明我记忆超群  计算能力强
I have high retention abilities and exceptional math skills.
上路了
You're getting it.
我就想嫁给克里斯托弗  给他生孩子
Well, I just wanna get married to Christopher and have his babies
把家里收拾得漂漂亮亮
and make the house look nice.
躺沙滩上晒太阳
Maybe in the sunshine, like on the beach,
周围都是美人
surrounded by, mmm, beautiful people.
你刚刚跟一个犯人说
Are you at all aware that you just told an inmate in prison
她应该去做教改官
that she should become a correctional officer?
你脑子有病吧
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我真的想做职业运动员
I do want to be a professional athlete,
但不是响指一打  说做就能做的
but you just don't snap your fingers and become that.
我想做精神病儿童医疗这一行
I was hoping to work with mentally ill children.
我能让他们知道未来将要经历的事情
I think I could offer some insight into what they might be experiencing
帮助他们恢复正常
and help them to heal and recover.
或许我要玩"拼趣"  听说有这么个东西
Maybe I'll Pinterest. I hear that's a thing.
拼趣  著名社交网站
我从时尚达人到现在穿监狱制服
I went from wearing a habit to wearing a prison uniform.
时尚大概已经不适合我了
I don't think the fashion industry would be a viable option for me.
我还喜欢和圆形物体在一起
I would also like to work with round objects.
我特别喜欢圆东西
Yeah, round things are very pleasing to me.
或许我可以给女子垒球当裁判
Maybe I can umpire women's softball.
然后就有艳福啦
Then I could get laid.
而且我还特会押韵  你说该怎么写呢
So I also can rhyme real good. What do I say about that?
具有诗歌特长
Poetic inclinations.
就才够意思  咱俩可以做好盆友
That's what I'm talking about! See, you and me, we gonna be friends!
来  来  走一个  就这意思
Yeah, give it to me! Give it to me! Yeah! That's what I'm talking about.
继续继续
Now let's keep going.
瓦西里  你脸怎么了
Vasily, what happened to your face?
甘亚的人干的吗
Did Ganya's people do that to you?
不是的妈  丽萨用零钱包砸的
No. No, Ma. Lida hit me in the face with a bag of change.
什么
What?
她有个装洗衣分币的袋子放在桌子上
She has this bag of quarters for the laundry sitting on the table.
我晚上喝醉晚归  她拿起袋子就砸我
I stumbled in late a little drunk. She grabbed it, and whack.
砸得好
Good for her.
妈  谢您老人家这么帮儿子
Yeah, I appreciate your sympathy, Ma, thank you.
我养你可没教你醉酒晚归惹老婆生气
I didn't raise you to come home drunk and upset your wife.
她不是我老婆
She's not my wife.
她是我孙子的妈  你说我怎么叫她
She's the mother of my grandson, what should I call her?
伤害你儿子的暴力犯
A violent criminal who hurt your baby boy.
-很疼来着  -为什么不娶她
- This hurts, Ma. - Why won't you marry her?
她人善良  又包容你
She's a nice girl, she puts up with you.
我害怕给人承诺
I have a fear of commitment.
好了妈  还是说说你吧
Okay, mamochka, why don't we talk about you for a little bit?
我的生活悲惨又狭隘
Because my life is sad and small
还给所有我爱的人带来负担
and a burden to those I love.
你爸没给我账户里存钱
Papa didn't put any money in the account this month.
-怎么回事  -想知道怎么回事
- What's going on? - Wanna know what's going on?
妈  店里根本没人来
Ma, the store is empty, okay?
大家都不敢来店里
Everyone's afraid to go in because they know
他们知道甘亚记恨你和爸爸
Ganya's mad at you and Pop
丢了监狱的生意
for blowing the prison contract.
这笔生意还是我给他的
I got him that contract in the first place.
是吗  那你可得提醒他一下
Yeah? Well, maybe you should remind him,
貌似他不记得了
because he doesn't remember that part.
你爸为什么不来
Why didn't Papa come?
他一直在店里  待到半夜
He's at the store all day, half the night,
就看有没有客人
he just sits there, waiting for someone to come in.
妈  没人能帮他
He's got no help, Ma.
那你为什么不帮他
So, why don't you help him?
妈  我也有工作  要养家糊口
Ma, I'm working. I got a family, too.
你以为我不想去帮他吗
Don't you think I wish I can go there and help him out some more?
我或许真该去上学
You know, maybe I should've gone to college like you said.
尤里和马克西姆呢
What about Yuri and Maxim?
都在上班  忙着糊口呢
We're all working. We're all hustling.
都忙着对付手拿武器的泼妇们
We're all trying to avoid crazy women with weapons, okay?
现在是艰难时刻  我要想想办法
It's just rough times right now. I'm gonna put some things together.
下周一定给你汇钱  我保证
I'll get you money next week, I promise.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是个好儿子  不是多好  但也还行
You're a good son. Not great, but pretty good.
这就够了
I'll take it.
天啊  她已经大变样了呢
God, she already looks so different.
-是啊  -你好呀
- Yeah. - Hello!
没错  我就是你妈咪
Yeah, that's right, I'm your mommy!
妈咪好爱你
And I love you so, so, so much!
马上咱们就能在一起了  妈咪保证
And soon we're gonna be spending lots of time together, I promise.
在你记事前妈咪就能和你团聚了
Before you can even remember stuff, we're gonna be together.
你说几岁  几岁开始记事呢  四五岁吧
When is that? When you can remember? Like, when you're four or five, right?
我四岁就能记事了
I think I remember something from when I was four.
不知道
Don't know.
她头上真香
Her head smells so good.
长得像你  但是很漂亮
And she looks like you, you know, but pretty.
她乖吗
Is she a good baby?
-睡得香  吃得好吗  -挺好
- Does she sleep okay? Is she eating? - Yeah.
-和你聊天真开心  -是嘛
- It's so good talking to you. - Yeah.
我一点儿不担心  分分钟搞定面试
See, I ain't worried. I'm gonna rock that interview,
成为招聘会胜者
then I'm gonna be the winner of the job fair
然后就能找到真工作了
and they gonna hook me up with a real job.
我要当法制节目里的法官助理
I'm gonna be like an assistant to Judge Joe Brown
给如乔・布朗
or one of them TV judges.
甚至朱蒂法官做助理
Or maybe even Judy.
《法官朱蒂》  美国著名电视法庭调解节目
她谁都不
Yeah, man, she don't take shit from nobody!
我们肯定合得来
I know we'd vibe.
你扯哪门子的淡呢  还真工作
Yo, what the fuck are you talkin' about, real job?
去年招聘会的胜者
Last year, the girl who did the best,
一出狱就有人给找了工作
the job fair people hooked her up with a real job once she was released.
她们没有声张是因为不想大家炸毛
They don't announce it or nothing 'cause people get all crazy,
但她悄悄跟我说了
but she told me on the low-low.
-去年谁赢了  -波卡诺
- Wait, who won last year? - Pocano.
-奥坎珀  -就那个长痣的菲律宾妞儿
- Ocampo? - The Filipino chick with the mole?
奥坎珀
Ocampo.
就是木工铺的那个
Man, the one that worked in the woodshop.
她赢了最佳着装  并且被评了最佳简历
She won for best outfit, and she had the best resume.
你干嘛不告诉大家还有奖品
Why didn't you tell us there was a prize?
你想什么呢  大家都在竞争好不好
Man, why you think? We are the competition.
现在我们出局
Now we out the way,
明天就剩她和那个墨西哥瘦子
so it's just her and the little skinny Mexican
去参加面试
doing the interview tomorrow.
太不地道了  你应该告诉大家的
Man, that shit ain't right, man, you should've told us.
我是体制外长大的孩子
But I'm a child of the system,
也没人没教我怎么辨别是非
no one ever taught me right from wrong.
滚一边儿去
Girl, fuck you!
你穿那身土豆麻袋能好到哪去
Like you would've did better in your potato sack?
我终于争取到这个机会  我会为大家努力的
Man, I got a chance here, and I'm doing it for all of us.
拜托  我需要大家的支持
Man, come on! I need y'all rootin' for me.
不能让瘦豆子赢
We can't let Skinny Bean win.
她们已经夺了厨房
They already got the kitchen,
电影夜也占了最好的座位
and they got the best seats at movie night.
-没错  -没错
- True. - True.
难道这个机会也让他们抢去
Y'all gonna let them take this, too?
给过你机会  给了你好几次机会
You had your shot. You had several shots.
现在知道改主意了  快出去
Now you got a change of heart? Get outta here.
我在那里待不下去了
I can't stay no more in that place,
我不能再去一个新家重新开始
and I can't start over in another home.
不好意思打扰了
Excuse me, ma'am?
我来店里想买点泡泡纸
I was just walking through your store, hoping to buy some bubble wrap
然后给我卡罗莱纳州的阿姨寄点巧克力
and maybe ship some chocolates to my aunt in Carolina.
指巧克力味的大麻
我能卖给你的只有泡泡纸
And that's about all I'm gonna sell you, is some bubble wrap,
其他的  恐怕你来错地方了
anything else, you've got the wrong shop.
好好的这是哪一出呀
What you talking about? We all good.
我上个月还了你800块
I paid you $800 last month.
真的吗  要我亲自去查账吗
For real? You gonna make me go to the books?
他付了你800块对吗
He paid you $800, right?
那之前商量的价钱是多少
What was the initial agreed-upon price for the quantity in question?
瞧瞧  又开始炫耀了
Well, look at you, using your big words.
1250块  之前还欠我130呢
$1,250. Plus, he owes me $130 from before.
1250加130  他还欠你580
$1,250 and $130. He in the hole to you for $580,
除非还有利息
unless there's a vig.
当然有利息
You can bet your ass there's a vig.
那么就是182块
So that would bring it up to $182,
加上1250块分期付款的50块罚金
plus $50 penalty for partial payment on the $1,250,
所有加一起是682
now we talkin' $682.
脑子太好用了
Fuckin' Goldberg over here.
拜托了维  我还有客人等着呢
Come on, Vee, I got customers waitin' on me.
你是我的批发货源  得帮哥们儿一把
You're my wholesaler. Help a brother out.
你说呢
What you think?
我看他挺着急的
I think he seem pretty desperate.
要我说  先给他一半货
I say give him half now
还清了再给另外一半
and the other half when that debt drops to zero.
真他妈操蛋
This is fucked.
小心点儿
Careful, now.
他现在一共欠1307块
He up to $1,307 now.
周末前来找我
You find me by week's end.
看来在快餐店收零钱
Well, looks like adding up all them little nickels and dimes
还真让你学了不少东西呀  美味
at Burger McFat-Ass done taught you a thing or two, huh, Taystee Girl?
准备好上班了吗
You ready to work?
我去查库存
I'm gonna go check on inventory.
-嘿  -谢天谢地  进来吧
- Hey. - Oh, thank God. Come in.
-带啤酒了吗  -皇冠对吗
- Did you bring the beer? - Coronas, right?
不对  不对  黑啤酒
No! No, no, no, dark beer.
应该是黑啤酒  帮我下奶
It's supposed to be dark beer. It helps my milk come in.
莱瑞  我又不做鱼肉玉米卷
I'm not making fucking fish tacos, Larry.
我要给孩子喂奶
I'm trying to feed my child.
还带了黑啤酒  谢谢
And you brought the dark beer, thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
对不起  我都快疯了
I'm sorry, I'm going bat-shit.
波丽  你的胸...
Uh, Polly, your breast is kind of...
一直都露外面啦  快递最爱来的就是我家
Please, they're always out. I'm the UPS guy's new favorite stop.
你有联系帕波吗
Hey, have you talked to Piper at all?
没有  你知道的
No, and you know that.
我知道你俩分手了
And I know you broke up.
听说她吓得半死  又蹲了"金币"[禁闭]
And I know she freaked out and got sent to live in a shoe or something,
现在又去了芝加哥  她最讨厌深盘披萨了
and now she's in Chicago. She fucking hates deep-dish.
可不是嘛
I know!
这些都是她妈告诉我的
Well, I heard all this from her mom.
莱瑞  她是我朋友
Look, Larry, she's my friend,
所以我永远都站她那边
and I'll always take her side over yours,
我们朋友很多年
and I'll always be friends with her,
谁知道以后能和你熟络几年
and who knows how long I'll know you?
这话就咱俩说  我觉得她太傻了
But just between us, I think she's being an idiot
简直是自取灭亡
and self-destructive and stupid,
这件事上我完全支持你
and my sympathies are with you all the way on this one.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
谢什么  我啥也没说
For what? I never said a thing.
我不能和你论帕波的长短
I don't talk about Piper with you.
不忠诚也不合适
That would be disloyal and wrong.
明白
Gotcha.
皮特什么时候回来
So, when is Pete back?
不知道  以后他也甭想回来
I don't know, I may not let him come back.
孩子才三个月
The baby is less than three months old
他却忽然要去苔原取景
and suddenly he has to go on a vision quest in the fucking tundra?
说句公道话  他说是你让他去的
Well, to be fair, he said you told him to go.
我是荷尔蒙混乱  又不是真心的
I'm a hormonal moron! I didn't mean it.
谁知道他真去了
I didn't think he would actually go.
莱瑞  我都三天没洗澡了
I haven't showered in three days, Larry.
我妈这一周都去参加什么纸牌比赛
My mother is in a fucking pinochle tournament for the whole week,
虽然她在家也没怎么帮上忙
not that she's any help when she's here,
我想更多亲子接触
and I don't have a goddamn baby nurse
所以也没请保姆
because I'm trying attachment parenting,
全部都是扯淡
and it's fucking bullshit.
趁他还没被我的眼泪和汗水淹死
Here, take this child
帮我抱一会儿
before I drown him in my tears and sweat.
嘿  小宝贝儿
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, hello.
宝贝儿你好
Hello, baby, hi,
我是你莱瑞叔叔
it's your Uncle Larry.
你还好吗  今晚叔叔陪你玩哦
Hi, how's it going, buddy? We're gonna hang out tonight, man, yeah.
咱们订点泰国菜
We're gonna order some Thai food,
再看会儿电视  怎么样
maybe watch a little TV. How's that sound?
喜欢吗
Cool with that?
我要去冲个澡  你能给他换下尿布吗
I'm gonna take a shower. Can you change him?
可以啊  我试试看
Yeah, I mean, sure, I can try.
好
Okay.
他很干净  还好吧
He's all new and just happy.
别担心  皮特和我分分钟都能搞一团糟
Yep, don't worry, Pete and I will fuck that right up.
是真的吗
No, is that true?
不是吧  你要乖乖的哦
Come, now. That's not true. You stay happy, buddy, okay?
要乖乖的好吗
You just... you just stay happy, all right?
这主意还是因为你小时候
You know, I got the idea from when you was a baby.
那会儿谁都不能给你酸奶吃
No one was allowed to ever give you yogurt,
因为你一吃就止不住得拉
'cause you would, like, fucking explode.
拉得到处都是
There'd be shit everywhere.
后背  头发都有  特别恶心
Up your back, in your hair. It was so disgusting.
现在居然派上用场了
But now it's coming in handy, right?
你说是吧
Right?
有用吗
Is it working?
你就不能给我点隐私吗
Could you just please give me some privacy here?
你这样让我很不自在
You're making me really, really uncomfortable.
我是你妈诶
I'm your mother.
天啊  拉个屎都没得清净
God, can I just shit in peace?
好吧
Fine.
但只要有动静  你就告诉我
But if you have any action, you let me know, okay?
-人家关心你嘛  -好答应你  快走吧
- I fucking care. - Fine, fine, just go.
好了  站起来
All right, here, stand up.
这样腰部应该合适一点
This should fit you better around the waist now.
谢谢你帮我  珀比
Yeah, thanks for lookin' out, P.
为家人  不都这样嘛
It's what you do for family.
是吗  那你现在是我的疯姨妈珀比吗
Yeah, what, you my crazy Aunt Poussey now?
不对  我是你姐们儿
No, I'm your sister from another mister
要是敢不好好背书
about to beat your ass down
就揍你个屁股开花
if you don't read that book till you know it cold.
你可是要去面试的人
You got some interview ass-kickin' to do.
要让我为你骄傲
Make me proud.
猜猜谁回来这么开心
Guess who's back and better than ever? Hey!
我知道你让去买标识
I know you said to get AnyStamp,
但好必来简直太好玩了
but the hobby shop was mad fun, yo!
你们进去过吗
You ever been in there?
我想把那些手工都买下来  有棉花彩
Made me wanna get all crafty, get some puffy paint,
还有串珠机
or a rhinestone machine.
里面还有一整个货架的洗管器
They had a whole fucking aisle of pipe cleaners!
洗管器诶
Pipe cleaners!
在教养院  我们只有断蜡笔和快干掉的胶棒
Man, in group home, all we got was broken crayons and dried up glue sticks.
那咱们是要给货袋做标记呢
Are we marking scag-bags
还是装饰你的日记本呢
or we decorating your journal?
不知道  维
I don't know, though, Vee.
或许你可以考虑用这个当你的商标
I mean, maybe you wanna consider one of these for your trademark, you know?
每个袋子粘两个
Glue a pair of these on every bag,
或者叫"瞪眼大麻"
or call it googly smag, you know?
儿童手工里常做"googly eye"
很拽的
Shit's all gangster!
好吧  我知道我是有点高兴过头
All right, maybe I got a little carried away,
但你看这只多可爱
but look how cute this one is.
零钱给我行吗
Can I have my change, please?
我给你张百元大钞不是让你去买手工眼睛的
I did not send you to the store with a C-note to bring back googly eyes.
好吧
Okay.
但说正经的
But for serious,
为什么不能用其他东西做标识呢
like, why couldn't you use something different for a stamp?
比如猫头鹰先生
Like Mr. Owl here?
大家不都吃这套吗
People do this shit, right?
好货上面都有眼花缭乱的包装
Like, there's dope with all sorts of crazy shit on it.
这跟你怎么包装没关系
It's not about what you put on the package,
关键是看货的品质
it's about the quality of your product.
她说得有点道理
I don't know, though, she kind of right.
你包装够怪
You pick something weird,
人家以后就记住了
people gonna remember that shit for sure.
猫头鹰像喝醉了
That owl looks drunk.
还是马和自行车吧
I like the horse and the bicycle.
好吧  那就用马吧
Okay, say we use the horse.
那咱们的货就叫"马货"
Call our shit Horsey Horse, get it?
因为海洛因被称为马  等着财源滚滚来吧
Because heroin's called horse. Yo, that's money!
我告诉你  到时候  人家就这样
I'm telling you, people be like, "Ooh,
"我要来点马货  那玩意儿超正"
"I need me some more of that Horsey Horse. This shit was so good!"
等你还没意识到  咱们的货就成名牌了
Before you know it, you've got a call brand.
看这丫头开始教我怎么做生意了
Listen to her trying to teach me how to deal.
你们别笑  我告诉你们
Y'all laughing now, but I'm telling you,
等以后混到华尔街  我请你们去开开眼
come visit me one day when I'm on Wall Street
我要让白人小伙子给我买早餐
and having some white boy get me lunch,
我一边谈大生意  那小伙子一边说
and I'm wheelin' a big old deal, and he talking about,
"杰斐逊小姐  二号线上有人找"
"Ms. Jefferson, you have a call on line two."
电影看多了吧
Think you've been watching too many movies.
这不是我的终生职业
I'm just saying, yo, this is not my forever career.
姑娘  这里的人
Girl, you from this hood,
没有职业  有活干就不错了
you don't get a career, you get a job.
这还是附近最赚钱的活
This right here is the best-paying job around.
又开始说教了  维
Preach it, Vee.
你知道大家最看重的是什么吗  钱
You know what people respect? Money.
你跟着我干  钱保你赚够
You keep working for me, that's exactly what you gonna have.
你说呢RJ  我是不是挺照顾兄弟们的
Ain't that right, RJ? Don't I take care of my people?
-当然  -爱怎么说怎么说
- Yes, ma'am. - Eh, whatever.
尝尝看  要不要加盐
Look here, taste this, girl. Tell me if it needs some more salt.
-真好吃  -我就知道
- Mmm! That is good. - I know.
里面什么东西  南瓜吗
What's that, pumpkin?
胡桃南瓜汤加姜
Butternut squash and ginger,
-我还扔了两片韭菜  -好吃
- and I threw in some leeks, just 'cause. - Mmm!
好了RJ  收拾桌子  来端沙拉
All right, now, listen, RJ, clear off that table, grab this salad.
-还有谁回来吃晚饭吗  -应该就我们仨
- Is anybody else coming home for dinner? - Uh, think it's just us.
拿几个碗
All right, grab some bowls, please.
太好了  这个太香了
Oh, yes, ooh, this smells good.
拿盘垫  妥了
Get the placemats. All right.
"马货"
"Horsey Horse".
挺好玩  但是太傻了  跟你一样
That's kind of fun. But, Lord, have mercy, it's silly, just like you.
我今晚弄了一种新面包
I tried a new bread tonight, y'all.
全谷物亚麻仁面包
It's a whole grain flaxseed bread.
你们的饮食里要多来点纤维
Y'all need some more fiber in your diet.
美味  拿把刀来切面包
Grab a knife for this bread, too, Taste.
快拿碗呀姑娘  磨叽什么呢
Bring the bowls, girl. What you waiting for?
红妈
Hey, Red.
这座位真好  可以看见舞台
These are great seats, you can really see the stage from here.
你们何必这样呢
You really don't need to do this.
我感激你们这样示好  但...
I mean, I appreciate the gesture and everything, but...
但什么  怕被流放还是怎样
But what? We'll be ostracized?
反正已经没人注意了
Already no one notices us.
我们都老了  没人注意
We're old and invisible,
干嘛不一起做伴老去呢
so why not be old together?
互相陪伴
We keep each other company.
你说我老
You calling me old?
老娘才23呢
I'm 23.
那就成熟吧  像一颗枝繁叶茂的大树
How about matured? Like a big, branchy tree.
树根全白
With snow-white roots.
妈的  我得想办法收拾一下
Oh, shit. I gotta deal with that, huh?
让它白吧  甭管了
Or just let it go. Fuck it.
你还想博谁眼球呢
Who we trying to impress?
她这23岁也太残了吧
She looks rough for 23.
这是去哪里
Where we going?
进城
We're going to town.
真的吗
Really?
医疗中心  给她做口腔手术
Medical center. She's going to the oral surgeon.
希望你杂志带得够多
Hope you got lots of those magazines,
因为这一去得很久很久很久
'cause it's gonna be hours and hours and hours.
我带了好多呢
Oh, I got plenty.
我还有广播剧  够了
And I got my radio shows. I'll be fine.
德盖特  好事哦
Good for you, Doggett.
-公喜公喜  -谢谢
- Congratu-fucking-lations. - Thank you.
没错
That's right,
菲利普・莫里斯公司相信第二次机会
we at the Philip Morris Companies believe in second chances.
菲利普・莫里斯  世界第一大烟草公司
对于那种能够在严苛环境下
We welcome people who can handle the challenges
生产并销售这种成人产品
of manufacturing and marketing products meant for adults
而且每时每刻牢记社会责任的人们
in a highly regulated and restricted environment
我们永远表示欢迎
while striving each day to operate responsibly.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
我以为特邀嘉宾是莫妮卡
Man, I thought special guests meant like Mo’Nique
Mo'Nique  莫妮卡  美国著名黑人喜剧明星
或者韦斯利・斯奈普斯之类的
or Wesley Snipes or somethin.’
韦斯利・斯奈普斯  美国影星
代表作《死亡游戏》  《刀锋战士》
谁知道是这种本来已经
Not some cigarette-hawkin' fuck-nut reminding us
"人人喊打"的烟草公司
that the only people who want to hire felons
来告诉我们  只有他们才会招前科犯
are already hated by everybody else.
不对  还没你说的那么糟
Nah, see, they ain't so bad.
人们可以自己决定抽不抽烟
See, people can decide for themselves if they wanna smoke.
真正的邪恶的是那些
The real evil are them companies
未经同意谋害性命的公司
killin' us without consent.
孟山都  力拓  大型医药公司
Monsanto. Rio Tinto. Big Pharma,
英国石油  哈利伯顿
BP, Halliburton.
我一直都有读这些大公司的幕后丑事
I been readin' there's some dark shit goin' down.
这些操蛋公司当然不会雇我们
Not that any of 'em motherfuckers ever wanna hire us.
但真正的罪犯根本犯不着惹我们这等屁民
But the real criminals, they don't bother with us small-timers.
现在斯洛文先生要面试这两位"准员工"
And now Mr. Slovin will "interview" two "prospective employees".
女士们  这环节能让你们学到很多
Many lessons to be learned here, ladies.
注意听
Please pay close attention.
你好  感谢两位的来访
Hello, and thank you for coming in today.
您也好
Well, hello to you, too.
您好  感谢您今天能够抽空见我
Hello, and thank you so much for taking the time to see me today.
我经历过的最佳上司
The best boss I ever had?
应该是厨房的歌洛丽娅
I would have to say Gloria in the kitchen right here
因为她很讲条理
because she's really organized,
而且她很懂音乐
and she plays real good music.
我最大的长处是态度积极
My greatest strength, I'd have to say, is my positive attitude,
还有我超强的记忆能力
and my aptitude for rote memorization.
我看什么都过目不忘
I see something once, and I got it down.
我能够高效地利用时间  几乎从不迟到
I use my time very efficiently. I'm almost never late.
她今天就迟了
She was late today.
我之前那份工作上  有一位长期客户
For example, in my old job, a long-term client
就要把单子交给我们的竞争对手时
was about to take his business to a competitor.
我去和客户谈
I was able to meet with the customer
改变了我们处理账户的方式
and change the way we handled his account
就是为了保住这单生意
on a day-to-day basis in order to keep the business.
我觉得和同事
I think it's important to have close,
保持亲密的关系很重要
intimate relationships with your co-workers.
对聚拢人心很有帮助
It's good for morale, you know?
这是犯规
Okay, that's, like, a foul.
很高兴和两位见面
It was lovely meeting both of you, thank you.
谢谢你  斯洛文先生
Thank you, Mr. Slovin,
如果能为菲利普・莫里斯
and may I say what a privilege it would be
这个从1983年至今
to work for the Philip Morris Corporation,
一直是美国最大的烟草商
a company that has remained the largest cigarette manufacturer
44年来分红翻了46番的公司工作
in the US since 1983,
将是我莫大的荣幸
plus has increased its dividends 46 times in the last 44 years.
你们在全世界都想整倒你们的的情况下
You all tore this market up in the face of a world
在整个市场攻城拔寨
that was trying to tear you down.
这才是我想去的公司
Now, see, that's the company for me.
-好样的  -美味姐好样的
- Yeah! Yeah! - Yeah, Taystee!
谢谢你  杰斐逊小姐
Thank you, Miss Jefferson.
请大家再次为杰斐逊小姐
Yeah, yes, let's hear a round of applause for Miss Jefferson,
和冈萨雷斯小姐鼓掌
and Miss Gonzales.
美味姐  美味姐  美味姐
Taystee! Taystee! Taystee!
他们需要这张照片
They gonna need that picture, boo.
我害怕看他躺在那里
I'm afraid to see him lying there.
你一看到他  就不会这么害怕了
I think once you see him, you won't be scared.
他还是咱们的RJ  只是不在那具皮囊里
He's still our RJ. He's just not in that body anymore.
但葬礼一过  他就真的走了
But it's like, once the funeral is over, he's really gone, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
那孩子是我一手养大的
I raised that boy.
亲眼看着他
Watched that smile go
从乳牙参差长成帅气小伙
from snaggletooth to lady-killer.
他帅得能把水里的鱼都吸引出来
I swear he could charm the fish out of water.
他们怎么能逃脱罪责
Man, how can they get away with this?
就没有人管吗
Ain't nobody gonna do nothing?
警察说他携带武器
Cops claim he was armed.
我不知道  或许他真带了
I don't know, maybe he was. I...
我告诉他身上别带枪
I told him to not carry a piece.
晚上到处乱逛的黑人小伙子
A black man walking around this city at night...
我们还计划一起去自由女神像
We had plans to go to the Statue of Liberty together.
我俩都没去过
Neither of us ever been.
我们还预约了步行走到神像头顶
We had reservations to walk up into the head and everything.
好傻呀
So stupid.
我带你去
I'll take you.
有我呢  美味
I got you now, Taystee Girl.
你保证不了
You can't promise that.
我会保护我自己的孩子
I protect my babies.
这是个意外
This one got away,
但我对你发誓
but I swear to you,
除非我死  否则这事不会有第二次
I will die before I see that happen again.
我会保你安全
I will keep you safe.
走吧  走吧
Come on, come.
来  有我呢
Come on, I've got you.
-怎样  -进展怎样
- Well? - How'd it go in there?
-拉出来了  -这就对了
- Victory. - Yeah! That's my girl!
真好  现在感觉好多了吧
Good for you, you must feel so much better.
感觉轻松多了
I just feel free.
是因为酸奶吧  当妈的才知道
It was the yogurt, right? A mother knows.
我给你的饮料已经在我家传了14代
The drink that I gave you has helped women in my family dookie
帮女人通便  药到病除
for 14 generations.
我觉得应该是两个都有
You know, I think it was a combination of both things.
不管怎样都无所谓  我现在真高兴
Whatever it was, it don't matter. I am so happy, you guys.
这是干什么呢
Hey, what's going on here?
-达娅终于拉出来了  -好大一泡
- Daya finally shit! - A big one.
她现在感觉好多了
She feels so much better now.
天啊  真极品  我的脸都被你们丢尽了
My God! I can't believe you guys! I've never been so humiliated. Jesus!
赶紧去啊
Well, go on.
去追她呀  告诉她没事儿
Go after her. Tell her it's gonna be okay.
好吧
Okay.
我们让她难堪了
We embarrassed her.
管它呢  当妈的哪个不让孩子难堪的
Whatever, happens, mothers embarrass their kids.
也对
Yeah.
对了  你从哪里搞的酸奶
Hey, where the fuck did you get the yogurt?
那么斯洛文先生  谁能得到这份工作呢
So, Mr. Slovin, who gets the job?
塔莎・杰弗逊小姐
Miss Tasha Jefferson.
这就对了  打你个屁滚尿流  瘦豆子
That's right! In your face, Skinny Bean!
管它呢  反正也没什么意义
Whatever, it don't even mean nothing.
我又不抽烟
I don't even smoke.
美味
Taystee!
好了  我们的招聘会到此圆满结束
Okay, and that concludes job fair.
谢谢各位  谢谢各位
Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
那我怎么联系人家工作的事呢
Hey, so, how do I get a hold of someone about that job?
什么
Excuse me?
工作啊  我听说赢了可以给介绍工作
A job. I heard you get hooked up with one if you win this thing.
赢了招聘会本身就是胜利
Winning is a victory in itself.
但奥坎珀去年被人介绍去做了前台
But last year, Ocampo got set up with some receptionist gig.
没有的事儿  这又不是竞赛
That's simply untrue. This isn't a contest.
你全力以赴是因为本该如此呀
You do your best because that's what you're supposed to do.
你们怎么就是不明白呢
Why is it so hard for you people to understand?
一个个就像小孩子
You're like babies.
"我的礼物呢"  "快看我"
"Where's my present? " "Pay attention to me."
"给我礼物"  "快把暖气修好"
"Give me things." "Fix the heat."
"建个健身房"
"Build a gym."
我又不是你们老妈  成熟点儿行吗
I'm not your goddamn mommy. Grow up!
为了奖励你的努力和成就
In acknowledgment of your hard work and success,
给你小卖部账户上加10块钱  好好花
an award of $10 will be added to your commissary fund. Enjoy.
这就行了
Yeah, that's something.
这就行了  谢谢你菲格罗亚小姐
That is something. Thank you, Miss Figueroa.
撞鬼
Oh, shit.